SAI Rolotech Smart Engines —
a near COPRA-class roll-forming engineering platform.
Designed for precision. Built for production.
Start by selecting your material —
Galvanised Steel DX51D —
and defining the section profile.
A lipped channel, 2 millimetre thick,
120 millimetres wide.
Load a saved project or enter parameters directly.
The station engine calculates 13 forming passes,
distributing bend angle incrementally across each station.
Watch the flower progression unfold —
each pass bringing the flat strip closer to the final profile.
Roll contour is generated automatically —
upper and lower rolls matched to the strip geometry.
Springback correction applied per pass.
Force, power and torque calculated at each station.
Bend allowance and flat blank width — calculated instantly.
Bill of Materials generated with shaft,
bearing and roll specifications.
Process card ready for the shop floor.
Tooling library saves your roll sets for reuse.
Export to DXF, STEP, or a full CAD pack — one click.
Advanced Process Simulation Precheck —
pass-by-pass stress, strain and contact analysis.
Defect probability, fracture risk, wrinkling
and edge wave flags — all instant.
FEA-ready solver decks generated
for CalculiX and Abaqus when you need full simulation.
720 automated tests. 29 engine modules.
45 live API endpoints.
SAI Rolotech Smart Engines —
engineering-grade precision, from input to export.